Guide to the Texas Music Collection
University of Houston Libraries
Texas Music Collection
1900-2010
1940-1969
05/2011-011
Brown, Andrew, 1969-
11.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The Texas Music Collection contains research files on the history of Texas music, particularly musicians and record labels, including the administrative and financial files of Duke/Peacock records, of the Houston area. Newspaper clippings, photographs, financial records, songbooks, and administrative files comprise the research files.
Biographical Information:
Andrew Brown is a Texas music historian who primarily writes biographies and histories of music artists and record labels for books, magazines, and album liner notes. Brown has also conducted interviews for major Texas music figures, including Huey Meaux.
Sources:
Artist Direct: http://www.artistdirect.com/artist/bio/andrew-brown/2573116
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Administrative records; Correspondence; Ephemera; Financial records; Interviews; Photographs; Publications (document genre)
Topical Term:
Music -- Texas -- History and criticism; Musicians -- Texas; Popular music -- Texas -- History and criticism
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
Duke-Peacock Records Publicity Photos and ACA Master Books digital collection
available at http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/2011_011
Scope and Contents
The Texas Music Collection contains research files on the history of Texas music, particularly musicians and record labels, including the administrative and financial files of Duke/Peacock records, of the Houston area. Newspaper clippings, photographs, financial records, songbooks, and administrative files comprise the research files.
The collection is divided into six series, which are arranged in order of volume of material, from most to least represented: I. Artists, II. Production and Events, III. Geography, IV. Genres, V. Reference, and VI. Ephemera. The Production and Events series is further divided into five subseries: 1. Labels and Studios, 2. Radio, 3. Producers, 4. Venues, and 5. Record Shops.
Detailed List of Contents
- Artists, 1900-2010
  Scope and Contents
  The Artists series contains files on various Texas music artists and typically contains biographical information and materials documenting their recording careers. Formats represented in this series include photographs, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and promotional materials.
  - Aguary, Rickey, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alley, Shelly Lee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alonzo y Sus Rancheros, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baca Orchestra, 1900-1936, 2005, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bar X Cowboys, 1944-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barnes, Benny, 1956-1957, 1995, 2007, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barnett, Spot, 1956-1957, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brower, Cecil, 1948-1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Texas Johnny, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Walter, 1950-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buskirk Brothers, 1930-1956, 1994, 2002, 2009, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Byrd and Bingo, 1945-1949, 1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Caceres, Emilio (Quintet), 1947-1955, 1970-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Christian, Ben and His Texas Cowboys, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Choates, Henry, 1946-1951, 2001-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
  - Circle C Band, 1949-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Colbert, Tiny, 1949-1958, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Crawford, Blackie and the Western Cherokees, 1950-1953, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Daffan, Ted, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Davis, Link, 1934-1959, 1971, 1979, 2000, 2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dee, Jimmy and the Offbeats, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Derrick, Jack, 1940-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Dexter, Al, 1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dickey, Tom, 1938-1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dixie Playboys, 1945-1946, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dunn, Bob, 1938-1951, 2000, 2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Epps, Earl, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Five Canadians, 1966-1967, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ford, Neal and the Fanatics, 1966-1967, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Ford, Neal and the Fanatics, 1966-1967, 1994-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Forse, Tom, 1957, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Freeman, Bill and the Texas Plainsmen, 1950-1960, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Gaines, Roy, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Garibay, Randy, circa 1996, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Goodall, Spud, 1940-1965, 2001-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Goree Farm Girls, 2003, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Haddock, Durwood, 1960, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harris, Hal, 1955-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Heap, Jimmy, 1948, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hendon, R. D., 1948-1954, 2004, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Heppler, Bob, 1947-1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Hess, Bennie and Troy, 1959-1976, 2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Hill, Goldie, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hofner, Adolph, 1940-1969, 1983, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Hopkins, Lightnin’, 1959-1968, 1992, 2000-2003, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Irby, Jerry, 1941-1950, 1996, 2004, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jacoby Bros., 1945, 1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Jenkins, Leon, 1935-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Jericho, Jerry, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Jerry and the Country Gems, circa 1960, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jimmy and Johnny, 1950-1963, 1993, 2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Johnson, Blind Willie, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Jones, Bob, 1950-1955, 1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Jones, Little Hat, 1998, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Kennedy, Shang, 1940-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Lee, Johnnie, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Leo and the Prophets, 1967, 2000-2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Magic Ring, The, 1967-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Mahoney, Don, 1950-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mando and the Chili Peppers, 1947-1957, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Marchiando, Pete, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Martinez, Johnny (Alameda Records), 1950, 2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - McIntyre, Chet, 1957-1965, 1993-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Miller Brothers, 1945-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Mitchan, Junior, 1961, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Miller, Frankie, 1950-1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Moving Sidewalks, 1966-1968, 1986, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mullican, Moon, 1945-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Nix, Hoyle, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Novack, Eddie, 1930, 1949-1976, 1994, 2001, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Novack, Red, 1950-1965, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ogg, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ortega, Nick, 1957-1969, 1995, 2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Owens, Calvin, 1999, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Payne, Leon, 1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Poovey, Joe, circa 1950s, 1998,undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pullum, Joe, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Raley, Leo, 1935-1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rambling Rangers, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Red River Dave, 1945, 1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ray, Buddy, 1945-1948, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Red Crayola, 2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Revard, Jimmie, 1937-1951, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rhodes, Jack, 1948-1996, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sahm, Doug, 1957-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Semien, Lee Ivory, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Spades, The, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Starkey V, Dave, 1965, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Stubbs, Jerome, 1954, 2007, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Stover, Smokey, 1953-1961, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Strength, “Texas” Bill, 1946-1950, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Tanner, Wayne, 1948-1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Texas Top Hands, 1940-1970, 1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Thompson, Hank, 1945-1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Thirteenth Floor Elevators, 1966, 1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Thursday’s Children, 1966-1967, 1997, 2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Tillman, Floyd, 1946-1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Touchton, Peck, 1950-1957, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Traits, The, 1961, 2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Tucker, Gabe, 1955-1961, 1981-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tune Wranglers, 1937-1951, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Tyler, “T” Texas, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Valentine, Cal, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Washington, Little Joe, 2001, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Whitley, Smiley, 1937-1945, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Williams, Curley, 1933-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Lester, 1941-1949, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Zeke, 1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Wills, Bob, 1950-1960, 1974-1981, 1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, Hop, 1960, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Wood, Smokey, 1936-1947, 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Wyble, Jimmy, 1950-1959, 2003, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Zakary Thaks, The, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Production and Events, 1924-2008
  The Production and Events series comprises a range of material documenting the production of Texas music and is further divided into subseries pertaining to: Labels and Studios, Radio Stations, Producers, Venues, and Record Shops.
  - Labels and Studios, 1924-2008
    - General studio files, 1967-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Allstar Records, 1958, 2010, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Audio Company of America - Master books, 1950-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Audio Company of America - Master books, 1950-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Audio Company of America - Master books, 1950-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Columbia - Session files, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Columbia - Texas Masters, 1924-1941, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Decca, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Decca - Coral session, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Administrative, 1951-1973, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Administrative, 1951-1973, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Administrative - Bland, Bobby, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Administrative - Hinton, Joe, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, December 1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, January–February 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, March–April 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, April–May 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, June–July 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, August–September 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, October–December 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, January–March 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, April–May 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, June 1964 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, July–August 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Financial, September–November 1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Assorted financial, 1950-1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Promotional, 1951-1967, 2003, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Promotional, 1951-1967, 2003, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Promotional photographs, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Publicity photographs A-F, 1940-1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Publicity photographs G-Z and unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Duke/Peacock Records - Royalties, 1956-1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Freedom Records, 1951, 1994-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Glenn Barber Recording Studio, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Gold Star Records, 1944-2006, undated (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
    - Harlem Records, 1960, 1975, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Burton, 1949, 1993, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - International Artists, 1970-1971, 2002, 2005, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Longhorn Records, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Macy’s Recordings, 1938-1950, 1991, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Opera Records, 1947-1951, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Picture Records, 1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Tantara Records, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Sarg Records, 1949-2006, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Sittin’ in With Records, 1995, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Star Talent Records, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Starday Records, 1954-2001, 2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Starday Records, 1954-2001, 2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - TNT Records, 1954-1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Radio, 1939-2005
    - Chambers, Vernon (KCOH), 1953-1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Frazier, Skipper Lee, 1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - KATL, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - McCaskill, “Rascal”, 2004-2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Rochon, Lonnie (KNUZ), circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - WIBW, Round-up, 1945, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - WOAI San Antonio, circa 1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Producers, 1959-2004
    - Ames, Roy, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Epstein, Abe, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Meaux, Huey - Biographical, 1959-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
    - Meaux, Huey - Huey P. Meaux and Charlie Booth vs. The United States of America, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
    - Smith, Major Bill, 1976, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Venues, 2001-2003, 2010
    - Eldorado Ballroom, 2001, 2003, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bill Mraz Dance Hall, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Record Shops, 2002
    - Rio Record Shop, 2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Geographical, 1925-2008
  The Geographic series contains files on major regions in Texas music. Photographs and printed material, especially newspaper clippings and newsletters, comprise the majority of the series.
  - Austin, 1937-1960, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Beaumont, 1937-1952, 1995-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Dallas, 1925-1957, 1997, 2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Dallas, 1925-1957, 1997, 2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Fort Worth, 1940-1959, 1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Galveston, 1937-1957, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Paris (Texas), 1946-1947, 2007-2008, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Port Arthur, Port Arthur News, 1937-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Tyler, 1939-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Texas (General), 1932-2008, undated (Box 8, Folder 14-20)
  - Texas (General), 1932-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Texas (West), 1947-1959, 1997-2002, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Waco, 1940-1959, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Genres, 1960-2006
  The Genres series contains files on Texas Rock and Zydeco music. Printed material, correspondence, and photographs comprise the bulk of the series.
  - Texas Rock, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Zydeco, 1984-2006, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Reference, 1946-2006
  The Reference series includes printed material, such as magazines and directories, used by Andrew Brown for his research on Texas Music. The music historian Mack McCormick also has a file in this series.
  - Mountain Broadcast, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Northside Highlights Magazine, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Not Fade Away Magazine, 1986, 1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Texas Music Collector, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Texas Music Industry Directory, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Union Directories, 1950-1993 (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
  - Western Swing Journal, 1997-2004 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - McCormick, Mack, 1962-2006, undated (Box 9, Folder 17-19)
  - Unfiled [labeled “Lost and Found”], 1966 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Ephemera, 1945-1967
  The Ephemera series contains oversize publication and promotional materials and photographs from the research files.
  - Music booklets, undated (Ovs box 1, Ovs folder 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1945-1959 (Ovs box 1, Ovs folder 2)
  - Posters, 1967, undated (Ovs box 1, Ovs folder 3)
  - Print publications, 1948-1967, undated (Ovs box 1, Ovs folder 4)